hyrecar.com 2016-05-14

# Privacy Policy

Insurance & Damages

PRIVACY POLICY 

Last revised: April 24, 2015HyreCar 

HyreCar provides an online marketplace for car rentals and leases. This Privacy Policy describes HyreCar’ commitments to you with respect to HyreCar’ use of information collected in connection with the HyreCar marketplace.While HyreCar may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, we will always abide by the terms of the Privacy Policy in place when we collected your information. Please note, if we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will provide you with notice concerning the changes either on this page or through some other reasonable method. 

**Information We Collect through the Marketplace**

As used in this Privacy Policy, the term “personal information” means information that specifically identifies an individual (such as a name, address, telephone number, mobile number, e-mail address, or other account number). Personal information also includes demographic information such as date of birth, gender, geographic area and preferences when that information is linked to other personal information that identifies the individual. Personal information does not include “aggregate” information, which is data we collect about the use of the HyreCar marketplace or about a group or category of products, services or users, if all personal information has been removed. 

When you offer your car for rent or lease through the HyreCar marketplace, we will ask you for certain personal information including your name, contact information and information about your car. We may also require additional financial information from you to facilitate payment to you and to process any filings required by applicable tax authorities. When you rent a car through the HyreCar marketplace, we will ask you for your name, contact information, payment information and information concerning your driver’s license and driver’s record. We will maintain records for a reasonable period concerning your registration with and use of the HyreCar marketplace, including any correspondence you have with us. 

We automatically collect certain information through the use of “cookies” or clear gifs. Cookies are small data files that are stored on a user’s hard drive at the request of a Web site to enable the site to recognize users who have previously visited them and retain certain information such as customer preferences and history. Clear gifs (also know as web bugs or web beacons) are small, invisible graphic images that may be used on the site or in emails relating to the site to collect certain information and monitor user activity on the site. If we combine cookies with or link them to any of the personally identifying information, we would treat this information as personal information. If you wish to block, erase, or be warned of cookies, please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn about these functions. However, if a browser is set not to accept cookies or if a user rejects a cookie, some portions of the site may not function properly. 

We reserve the right to review and store the communications you make through the site, including your postings on site pages and your communications to other members using the marketplace’s messaging capabilities. We may use those communications for internal purposes, including to better understand how members use the marketplace, as well as for security purposes. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we are not obligated or required to review any communications and make no commitment to do so or to take any specific action with respect to those communications. 

HyreCar also logs each visit to each web page on the site. The log may contain information such as the browser type you used, your Internet Protocol address, and the date and time of day of the visit. We may also log your cookie’s identification number and the URL of the last site you visited. This log informationis important for security, audit, quality improvement, as well as for monitoring the health of our marketplace. 

If your vehicle or a vehicle you rent or lease through the marketplace includes an in-car device, HyreCar will log and retain information recorded by the in-car device, such as location, mileage and other aspects of your use of the car during a rental period. If the in-car device is operated by a third party service, e.g. OnStar, that service may record information about your use of the car. The third party service will be solely responsible to you for its use of such information. Same conditions apply to our mobile device apps. 

**Use of Information and Information Verification**

HyreCar will use your personal information solely for its internal business purposes in connection with the provision of the HyreCar marketplace. That includes use of your information: to facilitate our administration and operation of the marketplace; to understand better how our users engage with the marketplace; to verify your account information; to process your requests and transactions; to provide you with information or services you request; and to inform you about other promotions or products or services we think will be of interest to you. 

HyreCar will use third party services to verify the personal information you provide to us and to obtain additional related information and corrections where applicable. You hereby authorize HyreCar to request, receive, use and store such information for a reasonable period of time. In addition, you agree that personal information provided by you may be linked together or merged with other personal information so that we may have a better understanding of your account information and your use of the marketplace. In any case, this Privacy Policy governs any information we maintain about you and your use of the marketplace. 

**Disclosure of Information**

HyreCar does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others. We will not share the personal information we collect from you through the marketplace with third parties except as described in this Privacy Policy. 

HyreCar enables car owners to offer and rent their vehicles to other individuals. If you agree to a rental or lease transaction through the HyreCar marketplace, HyreCar may provide your personal information to the other party in that transaction as reasonably necessary to facilitate the rental or lease. For example, HyreCar may provide your mobile phone number to facilitate communication or your photograph to facilitate identification. 

In addition to information verification providers described above, we may share personal information with vendors and service providers who are engaged by or working with us in connection with the operation of our site and marketplace and who need access to such information to carry out their work for us. In some cases, the service provider may be directly collecting the information from you on our behalf. HyreCar will endeavor to choose service providers that are well established and who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of any personal information the service provider receives. HyreCar is not responsible for the acts or omissions of its service providers and you agree to hold HyreCar indemnified from any such harmful acts that may occur. 

If HyreCar offers or promotes services in conjunction with another company, and you request those services (or additional information about them), you consent to our sharing your personal information with those parties. In those cases, we will only share the information reasonably needed to provide you with the applicable service. We may also share personal information with third parties when you give us your consent to do so. Information that is shared with third parties as described in this paragraph is subject to the privacy policies of those parties, which may differ from this Privacy Policy. HyreCar is not responsible forthe acts or omissions of those third parties. We encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them. 

HyreCar may compile aggregate information about the use of the marketplace. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and users’ needs so that we can better consider new features or otherwise tailor our marketplace. HyreCar may also share aggregate demographic information with advertisers and partners. This policy in no way restricts or limits our collection and use of aggregate information. 

HyreCar may disclose personal information in the good faith belief that we are lawfully authorized or required to do so, or that doing so is reasonably necessary or appropriate to comply with the law or with legal process or authorities, respond to any claims, or to protect the rights, property or safety of HyreCar, our users, our employees or the public. That includes actions we may take to protect HyreCar or our users from fraudulent, abusive, inappropriate or unlawful use of our site or marketplace. Information about our users, including personal information, may also be disclosed or transferred as part of, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition or in any other situation where personal information may be transferred as one of the business assets of HyreCar. 

You understand that when you use the site, information you post in your profile or in any other area of the site will be available to other users and in some cases may be publicly available. HyreCar reserves the right to utilize images from your posting in any of our onsite or offsite marketing material and all images are considered the property of HyreCar once provided to us by you in any format. 

**Security**

We have endeavored to put into place reasonable security measures in an effort to protect personal information while it is under our control. We are not responsible for any unauthorized disclosure of personal or other information caused by any third party. Your account information is accessible online through the use of a password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of our web site by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. 

**Updating your information or opt-out of emails**

If you wish to opt-out of marketing and promotional emails, please contact us at support@HyreCar.com. You may not opt-out of receiving service-related emails. If you would like to update your contact information, please use your Profile Page. If you have any trouble using the Profile Page, please contact HyreCar’ customer service at support@HyreCar.com. 

**Terms of Service**

**Car use –**

**Prohibited uses of vehicles**

Only approved HyreCar renters can book and drive a car while it is under a HyreCar reservation. To be an “approved HyreCar renter” means that the member has submitted his or her License information, the driving history continues to meet our eligibility requirements, and that the member is still in good standing. The renter of a vehicle may NOT allow any other person to drive the vehicle even if it is another HyreCar member. 

Engaging in any Prohibited Uses with a HyreCar vehicle will be grounds for fines, suspension and/or cancellation of your membership. It will also lower the renter's liability coverage to state minimum limits or nullify coverage where allowable by applicable state law; if the owner has encouraged the engagement in a Prohibited Use, HyreCar may close their account. 

**Prohibited vehicle uses and activities include:**

- Permitting someone who is not an approved HyreCar renter to drive a HyreCar vehicle. 

- Driving a manual transmission car without being expert in the use of clutches and manual transmissions. Note: If the drive train of a manual transmission car is damaged, the renter will be presumed to be at fault and will be held fully liable for repair of any damaged components of the car, with the clutch-related costs further detailed in this entry support.HyreCar.com 

- Allowing the HyreCar vehicle to be pushed or towed by anyone other than an authorized law enforcement or service vehicle. 

- Using a HyreCar vehicle to: to tow or push anything, other than on paved roads (whether "off-roading", driving on unimproved roads or parking areas, or otherwise), in any race, test, or competition, with the intention to cause damage, or with wanton, willful, or reckless disregard for safety, unless a reservation has been booked. Using HyreCar vehicles without reservations or outside your reservation time constitutes unauthorized use, during or due to use in the commission of a crime or any other illegal activity or purpose, o while the renter is under the influence of alcohol above the legal limit or any drug or medication under the effects of which the operation of a vehicle is prohibited or not recommended, when it has been loaded beyond its rated capacity or with more passengers than the vehicle has seat belts, outside the 50 United States; or without a valid license, or if you do not meet our Eligibility Requirements. It is your responsibility to inform us when your license is expired or suspended, or if you believe you may no longer meet our Eligibility Requirements, to transport any flammable, toxic, volatile, poisonous, dangerous or illegal substances, to transport a pet outside of a pet carrier that keeps all pet hair inside the carrier. 

- Making any alterations, additions or improvements to any vehicle. 

- Fueling a HyreCar vehicle with an improper type of fuel. 

**Pet Policy**

Pets are not allowed in cars without the owner’s explicit consent. If an owner reports that a renter has transported a pet without their authorization, the renter will be subject to additional fees and may have their membership revoked for violating the Terms of Service. 

**Smoking Policy**

**Renters or their passengers are not permitted to smoke in any vehicle in the HyreCar marketplace**. We take reports of smoking very seriously. If a smoke smell is reported by the owner within 12 hours after a reservation has ended, that renter will be fined up to $250. The renter may also be subject to removal from the community. Smoking medicinal cannabis or state approved recreational cannabis is also prohibited while in a HyreCar vehicle regardless of local legislation. This includes vaporizers in all forms. 

If there is a smoke smell at the beginning of the reservation, please report it via e-mail to support@HyreCar.com (with Subject line "Smoke Smell Prior to Reservation") at the very beginning of your reservation so that you are not held responsible for the violation. If the owner smokes in their car, it is their responsibility to include this information in the listing. If the owner fails to inform a renter that their vehicle smells of smoke prior to the beginning of the rental, the renter may be entitled to a full refund and the owner subject to a fee or removal from the community. 

**Stripe TOS**

Link to Stripe TOS: https://stripe.com/us/terms 

**Contact**

HyreCar welcomes your questions and comments about privacy, and what we do. Please feel free to e-mail us at support@HyreCar.com. 

If you need to reach us by mail, please write to: 

HyreCar, Inc. 

4732 3rd Street, Suite 200 

United States 

Attn: Privacy 

Thanks for using HyreCar!

  * Insurance Coverage is provided up to $300,000 CSL per accident while under a Hyrecar Business “contract” rent/lease agreement.
  * The Hyrecar Insurance provides NO Insurance Coverage while a “Transportation Network Company” (TNC) is providing the Insurance Coverage.
  * There is NO Hyrecar Insurance Coverage provided unless the Hyrecar business auto rental/lease agreement is in force.
  * Hyrecar Insurance Coverage is only provided for the Hyrecar contracted driver while under contract with Hyrecar to rent/lease the vehicle.  No other permissive drivers or operators are covered under the Hyrecar Insurance policy.
  * Uninsured/Underinsured (UM/UIM) and Personal Injury Protection (no fault PIP) are included only at statutory basic limits and only where required by law.  UM/UIM & PIP are excluded in all states where permissible by law.
  * An Automobile Owner that is contractually engaged with Hyrecar to rent/lease their vehicle to a “TNC” driver will be reimbursed for any damage to such vehicle while it is on an active Hyrecar agreement. Damages are subject to the actual cash value (ACV) of the vehicle.  Damages are limited to not more than the Actual Cash Value or a maximum of $25,000 per claim, whichever is less; subject to a deductible.  (See the terms of the Insurance policy for a complete description).
  * Normal wear and tear is not covered by any insurance.

I’d like a detailed explanation of insurance and protection provisions

HyreCar provides drivers with insurance to protect owners, renters and third parties. HyreCar’s coverage when ride sharing app is not switched on and/or rider is not in rented car.

Liability Insurance is obtained for each renter who rents a non-livery vehicle on the HyreCar platform. The policy meets the state’s minimum requirements during the rental period. Livery vehicles maintain their own policy through the fleet owner. The liability policy for non-livery follows the vehicle.

Liability insurance is issued in the renter’s name and is included in all rentals. However renters are still responsible for any damages regardless of insurance coverage. Coverage excludes any damage during the delivery period, all pre-existing damage, normal “wear and tear” of the vehicle, aftermarket items, and any personal items left in the car.

The renter is responsible to return the car on time and in essentially the same condition it was in when they first received it. If there is damage to the car at the end of the reservation, unless the renter has notified HyreCar of pre-existing damage by e-mailing pictures and a description to support@hyrecar.com at the start of the reservation, or has documented an agreement with the owner regarding pre-existing damage by using our “Pre-Rental Checklist” or similar means, the renter is primarily responsible for all damage. Any physical damage protection that insurance or HyreCar may offer is “secondary” or “supplemental” to renter’s obligations.

All insurance policies include a $1,000 deductible (unless a state minimum requirement is lower). In the case that insurance covers an incident or the incident is less than $1,000, the renter will remain primarily responsible for any shortage in coverage such as deductibles.

Please note, the deductible does not waive the renter’s liability of being primarily responsible for all damages.

For HyreCar’s insurance coverage, if the renter has violated the Terms of Service, engaged in any Prohibited Uses or otherwise intentionally, recklessly, or with wanton disregard, misused the car, the deductible limits described above will not apply and the renter will be liable for all physical damage up to the actual cash value of the car, in addition to all Related Costs. Furthermore, if the renter causes damage to the interior of the vehicle or causes mechanical damage (not normal “wear and tear”), the protections described above does not apply, and the renter will be liable for the full cost of the repairs or replacement, as well as Related Costs.

"Related Costs" may include all costs and fees permitted by law, including but not limited to, estimation or appraisal costs, storage fees, towing fees, repair or replacement costs, registration or transfer taxes, claims processing costs and all similar or associated costs, minus any residual salvage value that is collected. Claims processing costs by HyreCar is $550 per claim and applicable deductible. This is an administrative cost and does not go towards the damages. If a third party accepts total fault for the claim and that third party’s insurer processes it on behalf of the owner without substantial processing by HyreCar, the renter will be refunded the claims processing fee.

HyreCar’s insurance coverage is “supplemental” or “secondary” to any existing coverage the renter may have available through other sources (whether through a credit card, personal automobile, or other policy). In practice, this means that the renter is primarily liable, but can satisfy their obligations through these other sources, such that HyreCar will first collect the relevant deductible directly from the renter to pay towards the repairs or replacement cost.

If you have additional questions regarding selecting among these options, please consult your insurance professional, or contact us at support@HyreCar.com, and we will direct you to a broker.
